[Music] hi everybody welcome back
to the channel and today's video is
an alternative to making Turkish dondurma so
the stretchy Turkish ice cream without using
salp the Orchid root flower so let's get
started on this one and see where we end
[Music] up in the last video we made dond
durma which is the the stretchy ice cream
with salop the actual Orchid root flower and
mastic resin uh most people don't have those
to hand or even know where to get them and if
you could don't want to pay that money for it
this stuff was apparently pretty pricey you
know it was sent to me thankfully it was sent
to me by one of my patreon supporters actually
so if you want to support the channel I'll put
a link in the description below and here is
the patreon and Kofi links so you can help
support the channel make sure that we can
keep making these lovely ice cream videos
anyway this shouldn't take too long so what we're
going to do I got my recipe here in front of me
we're going to measure this all up and get
it in the ice cream machine nice and quick
I'm going to turn this ice cream machine
on so it's chilling while we're making the
base cuz this is no heat base as well so let's
just get it going in our Bowl we are going to
need milk 335 G I will put the
cups measurement for each in the
description for those that use
cups 3 35 G of milk 335 G of
cream now I found this recipe online I will put a
link I can't remember for the life of me where but
I will put a link in the description and probably
put a little thing on the screen here because this
came from a chef in the Philippines and sugar and
he ran a class about you know trying to create
this 100 what we'll do we'll do 100
g of sugar there's a little bit more sugar to come
yet so you know being a chef you'd like to think
that they know what they're doing as the internet
has proved to everybody that is not always the
case some professional chefs are amazing and
know everything there is to know others not
so much I'm not Chef I'm a bum in Cookie
Monster lounge pants that's who I am so
we've got 20 gr of sugar in here that's all
of the sugar we need our low Asal gallon gum
guar gum try and get the flavor free version if
you can doesn't really make a lot of difference
I actually can't taste Gua gum and ice cream
some people can some people can't um and we
need little bit of salt and then we're going
to flavor this one with an extract okay so
we don't need that we need this what do we
need we need to open our G and gum special
ingredients not affiliated just love their stuff
they do ship worldwide don't know what the cost
is still got family back in England so they
just bring it over them we need three ground
I'm reading the recipe so I apologies if You'
see me looking down here I'm reading the recipe
at the same time as I'm talking to you so we
need three G of our low AAL gallon gum Three
G and we also need three G of Go gum [Music]
now double bag apparently there is a connection
between guar gum and lo Gallen gum and it only
happens with these two ingredients apparently
so let's see there we go let's see if this
person is Right we've made the original the
OG version we know that turned out damn near
perfect even if I say so myself don't need
that going to take our little whisk mix up
the sugar and the gums obviously guar gum is
a cold processed stabilizer so we don't need to
heat it I have no idea about galling gum let's
have a look says it does require heating but the
original recipe did not heat so maybe that's an
important part this might end up being part two
of three so what we're going to do is let's get
the salt one right it's a very small amount
of salt that there we go so mix that up as
well and get it all in our bowl of
liquid goodness and we are going to
whisk this for 2 minutes right 2 minutes
in our machine is ready let's pour this
in churn to the same kind of texture
that the original version was chy I did
say I was going to add some extract I forgot
to put it in let's add it now literally just
started there we go vanilla extract
about 5 G okay we're kind of at the
same texture consistency that we were
with the last one so we're going to
do the same thing bowls come straight
out of the freezer um um I'm going to
use this but first we're going to decant that into
here and then we're going to whip it for 2 minutes
so let's go I'm not convinced of the
texture right now this is my first
time making this one I haven't had time to
try this so we're all going through this
together if doesn't work or
I don't think it produces
the right result then I'm going to
do it again whip for 2 minutes or
not try again get my
phone
definitely acts different I can't whip this
any longer it's it's going to be liquid Again
by the time by the time it goes in the freezer so
let's just decant this into a container get it in
the freezer gag gum takes a while to gagum does
create stretch anyway let let's not forget this
so whoever did actually create this recipe and I'm
sorry if you watching this I doubt you are gag gum
creates a certain amount of stretch regardless
of what else you add to it so if after all this
it's just the effect of the gag gum I'm going
to be very disappointed so let's just see look
it's it's very liquid
let's get that in a freezer we're
going to give it a good couple
of days to harden off and then
we'll come back and do the next
bit so see you in a couple of days it's
been a couple of days look at all the
sun coming through this is winter anyway
it's been a couple of days is this has
obviously gone off now just to recap
it had a really strange texture very
non-traditional ice cream recipe from a
chef you know this is a professional chef
so it is solid as a rock this stuff is hard
so you won't be able to see this on the screen
but it's got It's really weird kind of texture
to it anyway we're going to leave this out
let it soften a bit try and get it up to
the same kind of temperature which I you
know I guessed that somewhere like minus
10 otherwise it's not a fair comparison
so I'll come back when this is softened
enough to start doing stuff to it it's
only been 10 minutes and this stuff is
melting so straight away this just isn't a
direct comparison to actual traditional dma
it's incredibly
icy really
icy so part of that is likely
part of that is likly because the the person
that developed this recipe obviously didn't
think uh about how the low AAL gallon
gum should have been used correctly um
so with this whole no heat thing that's
wasted the gallon Gum g gum up The Gua
gum you can't I mean I can't taste it
but there's also not enough to create
some of that Gua stretch that it it gives
you uh you could probably just scoop this
normally let's have a
look yeah you can see it's very
dry you know um some ice creams
are dry in texture and that's caused by
a few reasons um most notably incorrect
solids and this is the problem that most
internet ice cream recipes have is they
don't account for any of this stuff they
they do this they they boil up some ice
cream It Off and then they take
their their blog thumbnail which I'm going
to do right now and I will put it on the
screen and up they go with amazing Turkish vanilla
ice cream without using blah blah blah blah blah
blah blah and from the picture it looks good
it look it looks creamy it it looks you know it
looks like it should taste delicious and then you
start to break it apart and it comes apart like
a I don't know how to describe it it kind of
comes apart you know like like chunks of ice wood
in shards rather than you know a cohesive mix and
that is just down to a bad recipe just stop eating
it this was this was a a big disappointment
you know I expected a little bit better from
a professional chef for an ice cream recipe
I have remembered where I got the recipe from
I'm not going to put the details on this video
at any stage so I've removed them from earlier
on I'm not about to slay a random person on the
internet for a bad recipe it happens you know but
I'm going to develop my own version of dond durma
using methods that I have tried and tested over
the years and with that in mind I'll come back
to this which will end up being part three of
homemade Turkish dondurma but likely in a month or
so sorry to disappoint people that were hoping for
something amazing from this I too was hoping for
better results it's crap but hey you win some you
lose some next video we are going to do a patreon
requested flavor um and this is going to be Kinder
Bueno so I'm not going to just do a standard
kind of ice cream cuz I never do if you want to
see what we do with that one stick around like And
subscribe if you want to support the channel these
are the patreon and Kofi details they're all in
the description as well and thank you for coming
along on this journey with me and I will see you
next time when we make Kinder Bueno ice [Music]
cream